## Aizza Viera

# **CURRICULUM VITAE**

aizzakatrina@zoho.com aizzakatrina.com

#### **SUMMARY**

A financial data analyst with a background in accounting, and experience in data/quantitative analysis and financial reporting. Strong knowledge of databases, information systems, and business processes with a track-record for adhering to deadlines. Demonstrated ability to explore, interpret, and extract value from data enabling effective strategic planning in business operations.

### **EDUCATION**

Data Analytics Certificate. University of California, Berkeley. 2018 B.A. Economics, with Accounting concentration. California State University, East Bay. 2016

#### **SKILLS**

Financial reporting and modeling. GAAP. Data analytics and visualization. Regression analysis. Machine learning. Root cause analysis. Web scraping.

Programming Languages: VBA, SQL, Python, C++, R, Mongo, Git, HTML, CSS, JavaScript

**Software**: Advanced Excel (vlookups, nested functions, charts and graphs, pivot tables), Tableau, Power BI, NetSuite, Jupyter Notebook, Power BI, Mode Analytics

#### **ANALYTICS PROJECTS**

**Live Earthquakes Map** - A map of fault lines and earthquakes around the world in the past 30 days, updated every 15 minutes. aizzakatrina.com/earthquakes\_map

**Equatorial Latitude** - Data visualizations of the weather of 500 random cities across the world and of varying distances from the equator. aizzakatrina.com/equatorial\_latitude

@iPlotBot - A Twitter bot that scan its account every five minutes for tweets received via mentions and in turn performs sentiment analysis on the twitter account specified in the mention. The Twitter bot then tweets a visualized sentiment analysis of the Twitter account's 500 most recent tweets. twitter.com/iPlotBot

**Education and Poverty** - A responsive visual analysis of the correlation between poverty and education in the United States. aizzakatrina.com/education\_and\_poverty

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Financial Operations Analyst. Jyve Corporation. San Francisco, CA 2020–2021.

Consultant. Nabis. San Francisco, CA. 2020.

Accounting Analyst. Origin House. Santa Rosa, CA. 2018–2019

Staff Accountant. The RealReal Inc. San Francisco, CA. 2017–2018

Junior Accountant. The RealReal Inc. San Francisco, CA. 2015–2017

Accounting Associate. Stay Winning Boutique. Fremont, CA. 2014–2015

Bookkeeper. McCaulous Inc. Napa, CA. 2012

Student Assistant. Department of Human Development and Women's Studies. California State University, East Bay. 2012

### **COMMUNITY SERVICE**

Promoter and Coordinator. Urban Women's Marketplace. Oakland, CA. 2014

Accounting Volunteer. Loved Twice. Oakland, CA. 2011–2013

Accounting Volunteer. Recovery Survival Network. San Francisco, CA. 2010